export const JEWELLERYA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The most ductile metal in the options is",
A: "gold.",
B: "pewter.",
C: "platinum.",
D: "silver.",
answer: "A. gold.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A kiln is used in firing clay bead jewellery because of its",
A: "high temperature.",
B: "low temperature",
C: "rigidity.",
D: "refractoriness.",
answer: "A. high temperature.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Select the precious metal from the options.",
A: "Copper",
B: "Brass",
C: "Pewter",
D: "Platinum",
answer: "D. Platinum",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Asphaltum is used in metal jewellery when",
A: "annealing.",
B: "etching.",
C: "soldering.",
D: "tempering.",
answer: "B. etching.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. A foundry is a workshop for",
A: "casting metals.",
B: "electroforming metals.",
C: "forging metals.",
D: "refining metals.",
answer: "A. casting metals.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Oxides formed on surfaces of metals during annealing are removed by",
A: "enamelling.",
B: "pickling.",
C: "fluxing.",
D: "etching.",
answer: "B. pickling.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The internal cutting of a design on a metal is achieved through",
A: "denting.",
B: "sawing.",
C: "filing.",
D: "piercing.",
answer: "D. piercing.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Pick the appropriate tool used to make a dent on a metal sheet.",
A: "Hammer",
B: "Rawhide mallet",
C: "Mandrel",
D: "Centre punch",
answer: "D. Centre punch",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Identify the material obtained from mineral source from the options.",
A: "Shells",
B: "Agate",
C: "Pearl",
D: "Bone",
answer: "B. Agate",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Worked-on metals are annealed in order to",
A: "remove fire scales.",
B: "harden it.",
C: "increase lustre.",
D: "soften it.",
answer: "D. soften it.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The design for a medallion showing informal balance is described as",
A: "asymmetrical.",
B: "equidistant.",
C: "justified.",
D: "symmetrical.",
answer: "A. asymmetrical.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The chemicals used to corrode metals are termed",
A: "fluxes.",
B: "mordants.",
C: "solvents.",
D: "gases.",
answer: "B. mordants.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. For best results in soldering, the borax used should be in the form of",
A: "flakes.",
B: "granules.",
C: "paste.",
D: "powder.",
answer: "C. paste.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. When drilling, small pieces of items are best held with a/an",
A: "hand vice.",
B: "engineer’s vice.",
C: "bench vice.",
D: "filler’s vice.",
answer: "A. hand vice.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Surplus material on a calabash pendant is best removed fry",
A: "sanding.",
B: "filing.",
C: "buffing.",
D: "scraping.",
answer: "D. scraping.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Select the lightest metal from the options.",
A: "Aluminium",
B: "Lead",
C: "Gold",
D: "Iron",
answer: "A. Aluminium",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Select the property which enables metals to become liquid when heated.",
A: "Ductility",
B: "Elasticity",
C: "Fusibility",
D: "Malleability",
answer: "C. Fusibility",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Blowtorch is an indispensable tool used for",
A: "pickling.",
B: "buffing.",
C: "soldering.",
D: "scorching.",
answer: "C. soldering.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. When a metal is heated beyond its critical point it",
A: "crystalizes.",
B: "expands.",
C: "liquefies.",
D: "twists.",
answer: "C. liquefies.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the strokes of the jeweller’s saw does the cutting?",
A: "Diagonal",
B: "Downwards",
C: "Sideways",
D: "Upwards",
answer: "B. Downwards",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Select the metal which has the highest resistance to corrosion.",
A: "Copper",
B: "Brass",
C: "Iron",
D: "Silver",
answer: "D. Silver",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Designs for fabricating jewellery items are derived through",
A: "aesthetic review.",
B: "analytic study.",
C: "continuous appraisal.",
D: "idea development.",
answer: "D. idea development.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. During fabrication, a broken clay jewellery item is joined by using a mixture of",
A: "clay and grog.",
B: "grog and latex.",
C: "sand and raisin.",
D: "water and clay.",
answer: "A. clay and grog.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The substance used for soft soldering is",
A: "borax.",
B: "killed spirit.",
C: "hydrochloric acid.",
D: "methylated spirit.",
answer: "B. killed spirit.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. To achieve the best results in enamelling the kiln should first be",
A: "cooled.",
B: "fired.",
C: "heated.",
D: "packed.",
answer: "C. heated.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The lustre of a metal jewellery is best seen when it is",
A: "buffed.",
B: "pickled.",
C: "anodized.",
D: "polished.",
answer: "D. polished.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Select the most appropriate tool for cutting paillons.",
A: "Tenon saw",
B: "Piercing saw",
C: "Shears",
D: "Pliers",
answer: "C. Shears",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The slicing of thick leather to thin layer for jewellery fabrication is referred to as",
A: "punching.",
B: "thonging.",
C: "tooling.",
D: "skiving.",
answer: "D. skiving.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Select an inorganic material used in making jewellery from the options.",
A: "Bamboo",
B: "Bone",
C: "Cane",
D: "Silver",
answer: "D. Silver",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Fluxes are applied on surfaces to be soldered to prevent",
A: "patination.",
B: "inflammation.",
C: "oxidation.",
D: "sublimation.",
answer: "C. oxidation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A jeweller evaluating his/her handiwork is doing",
A: "appraisal.",
B: "assessment.",
C: "perception.",
D: "appreciation.",
answer: "A. appraisal.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The brilliance of a metal ring is achieved by",
A: "burnishing.",
B: "enamelling.",
C: "hammering.",
D: "pickling.",
answer: "A. burnishing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. To temper a punch is to increase its",
A: "hardness.",
B: "length.",
C: "thickness.",
D: "temperature.",
answer: "A. hardness.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Calabash jewellery is finished by",
A: "dyeing.",
B: "glazing.",
C: "burnishing.",
D: "scorching.",
answer: "D. scorching.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Leather obtained from larger animals is referred to as",
A: "chamois.",
B: "hide.",
C: "skin.",
D: "suede.",
answer: "B. hide.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following attributes best promotes the work of a jeweller?",
A: "Patience",
B: "Religious",
C: "Neatness",
D: "Skilfulness",
answer: "D. Skilfulness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The style, design and methods of fabricating a chain is considered under",
A: "identification of products.",
B: "interpretation of ideas.",
C: "inventory of materials.",
D: "proficiency of techniques.",
answer: "B. interpretation of ideas.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following artefacts best complements a pendant?",
A: "Armlet",
B: "Hairslide",
C: "Necklace",
D: "Ring",
answer: "C. Necklace",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Effective packaging of jewellery item helps to",
A: "get more designs.",
B: "get more sales.",
C: "glamorize the content.",
D: "increase creativity.",
answer: "C. glamorize the content.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Costume jewellery are highly patronized because they are",
A: "inexpensive.",
B: "noble.",
C: "hallmarked.",
D: "durable.",
answer: "A. inexpensive.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]